var chapters = [
  { chapter: 5, title: "Innovation Process" },
  { chapter: 6, title: "Strategic thinking" },
  { chapter: 7, title: "Look to the future" },
  { chapter: 8, title: "Do the extraordinary" },
  { chapter: 9, title: "Ignite Passion" },
  { chapter: 10, title: "Take action" },
  { chapter: 11, title: "Different Thinking" },
  { chapter: 12, title: "It is in your hands!" },
  { chapter: 13, title: "Top Innovative companies" },
];

var allQuestionAnswers = [
  {
    question:
      "“Take these concepts and build them into fuller plans. Investigate resource needs, timing, and responsibilities.  Identify alternative plans”.",
    options: [
      "Step 5A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 6A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 7A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 8A of nine step innovation process",
    ],
    answer: "Step 7A of nine step innovation process",
    chapter: 5,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "“Explore commitment to the optimal plan. Identify who will support the plan. Prepare the plan for presentation”.",
    options: [
      "Step 2A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 3B of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 7B of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 8A of nine step innovation process",
    ],
    answer: "Step 8A of nine step innovation process",
    chapter: 5,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "“Release the final plan into action.Adjust the plan when needed”.",
    options: [
      "Step 1B of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 3B of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 7A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 9A of nine step innovation process",
    ],
    answer: "Step 9A of nine step innovation process",
    chapter: 5,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "“Choose the optimal plan based on the innovation goalposts and predetermined criteria. Consider the impact this plan will have on the rest of the organization”.",
    options: [
      "Step 3B of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 7B of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 7A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 9A of nine step innovation process",
    ],
    answer: "Step 7B of nine step innovation process",
    chapter: 5,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Choose the team that will address the problem. Gather facts, opinions, details. Apply “who, what, where, why, how, when” to the problem. Get information from external market.”\nThe above paragraph belongs to:",
    options: [
      "Step 1A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 1B of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 2A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 1B of nine step innovation process",
    ],
    answer: "Step 1A of nine step innovation process",
    chapter: 5,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "“Identify and list the likely causes of the problem. List “problem statements” or concerns. Do problem analysis”.\nThe above paragraph belongs to:",
    options: [
      "Step 1A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 1B of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 2A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 1B of nine step innovation process",
    ],
    answer: "Step 2A of nine step innovation process",
    chapter: 5,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "“Explore the range of acceptability for options and solutions. Do decision analysis”.\nThe above paragraph belongs to:",
    options: [
      "Step 2A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 3B of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 3A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 4B of nine step innovation process",
    ],
    answer: "Step 3A of nine step innovation process",
    chapter: 5,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "“Explore the environment for signals and other information. Research past, present, and future”. Explore multiple perspectives. Explore the marketplace”.\nThe above paragraph belongs to:",
    options: [
      "Step 4A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 3B of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 3A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 4B of nine step innovation process",
    ],
    answer: "Step 4A of nine step innovation process",
    chapter: 5,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Use your chosen stimuli and imagination to identify potential insights and discoveries. Suspend judgment while you are uncovering these insights. Use the creative connections power tools”.",
    options: [
      "Step 1A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 5A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 3A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 4B of nine step innovation process",
    ],
    answer: "Step 5A of nine step innovation process",
    chapter: 5,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "“Explore these high priority insights for potential ideas to solve your real problem”.",
    options: [
      "Step 1A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 5A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 3A of nine step innovation process",
      "Step 6A of nine step innovation process",
    ],
    answer: "Step 6A of nine step innovation process",
    chapter: 5,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which kind of decisions are based on:\n•\tAn understanding of customers’ current and emerging needs\n•\tAn understanding of organization’s current and emerging needs\no\tAnticipated future core competencies-special skills and knowledge\no\tAnticipated future resources and culture\n•\tFuture view of industry and marketplace",
    options: [
      "Fixation of product price",
      "Recruitment",
      "Strategic",
      "Retrenchment",
    ],
    answer: "Strategic",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who said it?\n"A general who wins a battle makes many calculations in his temple before the battle is fought."',
    options: ["William Shakespeare", "Sun Tzu", "Newton", "Churchill"],
    answer: "Sun Tzu",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The new model of strategic thinking which is an important component of Innovation Manage¬ment involves:",
    options: [
      "Executive team",
      "People who are believed to possess superior planning skills",
      "Everyone",
      "CEO and MD",
    ],
    answer: "Everyone",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Fill in the blanks:\nVarious elements of seeing the BIG Picture:\n1.\tSystems thinking\n2.\tClarify the real problem\n3.\tSet -------------------------\n4.\tBig picture criteria",
    options: [
      "Machines and equipment in order",
      "Innovation goalposts",
      "Right the process",
      "Up time reduction",
    ],
    answer: "Innovation goalposts",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the meaning of seeing the BIG picture?",
    options: [
      "To gather information by looking beyond the specific task",
      "Gathering information about the challenge from as many different angles as possible",
      "To truly understand the challenge at hand",
      "to see why your task is important to achieving the overall goals of the organization",
      "All the above",
    ],
    answer: "All the above",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Fill in the blanks:\n----------------- is a new way to view and mentally frame what we see in the world, whereby we see the entity first as a whole with its fit and relationship to its environment as primary concerns; the parts secondary.",
    options: ["Invention", "Systems thinking", "Strategy", "Creativity"],
    answer: "Systems thinking",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Who said it?\n"A problem well defined is half solved."',
    options: [
      "John Dewey",
      "Sir Humphry Davy",
      "Dave Eggers",
      "Dr. Vishva Dev",
    ],
    answer: "John Dewey",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find out the wrong statement:\nInnovation Goalposts can help the innovation process by:\n1.\tDirecting the innovation effort\n2.\tSetting expectations.\n3.\tFacilitating slow and steady decision-making",
    options: ["1 is wrong", "2 is wrong", "3 is wrong", "All are wrong"],
    answer: "3 is wrong",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is described below?\n“It is important to note that it is not one endpoint that players target; instead there are two between which there is a range of endpoints. How far should the they be from each other? The distance between them should not be so great as to confuse the par¬ticipants by encouraging them to go in too many different directions. Likewise, the distance between them should not be so narrow as to limit new ideas and approaches. There is a balance between being granted too much freedom, which may lead to too many random ideas, and too little freedom or over-direction, which could stifle innova¬tive thinking. Their goal of is focused creativity”.",
    options: [
      "Targets",
      "Objectives",
      "Innovation goalposts",
      "Big picture criteria",
    ],
    answer: "Innovation goalposts",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Fill in the blanks:\nSix BIG Picture-criteria:\n1.\tThe big idea must be simple.\n2.\tThe idea must support the overall business strategy.\n3.\tThe idea must be "distinctly new and better." \n4.\tThe idea must be proven.\n5.\tThe idea must be ------------------------\n6.\tThe idea must be quickly and easily implemented',
    options: ["Profitable", "Crazy", "Unconventional", "Out of the world"],
    answer: "Profitable",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The following examples belong to which of the Six BIG Picture-criteria?:\n1.\tThe Forum Shopping Mall in Singapore offers only children's stores and activities in order to differentiate it from the many other malls in Singapore.\n2.\tA tropical island provides the most interesting bicycle tours.\n3.\tA beer is unique because it is triple chilled during the brewing process.",
    options: [
      "The big idea must be simple.",
      "The idea must support the overall business strategy.",
      'The idea must be "distinctly new and better."',
      "The idea must be proven.",
    ],
    answer: 'The idea must be "distinctly new and better."',
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "If a manager at Starbucks decided to introduce pizza as a menu item for a new source of revenue, will it be OK for you if you are the CEO of Starbucks?",
    options: [
      "Yes, the idea is simple",
      "Yes, the idea is distinctly new and better",
      "No, It does not fit the strategic direction of the organization; Further, the idea is not easily implemented given the space requirement for additional equipment and the additional labor involved.",
      "Yes, the idea can be quickly implemented",
    ],
    answer:
      "No, It does not fit the strategic direction of the organization; Further, the idea is not easily implemented given the space requirement for additional equipment and the additional labor involved.",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Six BIG Picture-criteria  (Find out the wrong one)\na.\tThe big idea must be simple.\nb.\tThe idea must support the overall business strategy.\nc.\tThe idea must be "distinctly new and better." \nd.\tThe idea must satisfy seniors.\ne.\tThe idea must be profitable.\nf.\tThe idea must be quickly and easily implemented.',
    options: ["a is wrong", "b is wrong", "c is wrong", "d is wrong"],
    answer: "d is wrong",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "A recent television adver¬tisement for Honda communicated the big idea that the car had a Honda engine. The customer was confused because:",
    options: [
      "He wondered how Honda engine was distinctly new and better than a Toyota or Nissan engine.",
      "There is nothing special, Honda car will always have Honda engine.",
      "Honda engine will be expensive compared to Toyota or Nissan engines",
      "He wondered why ad is necessary.",
    ],
    answer:
      "He wondered how Honda engine was distinctly new and better than a Toyota or Nissan engine.",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'A recent television adver¬tisement for Tide communicated the big idea that “the product had blue packaging" or "the product was available in three sizes." What should be the punch line instead of these lines?',
    options: [
      "These punch lines are good enough",
      "It should be “Tide gives you the whitest clothes”",
      "It should be “Tide has added bleach”.",
      "It should be “Buy 5 get 6 free”",
    ],
    answer: "It should be “Tide gives you the whitest clothes”",
    chapter: 6,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Consider speaking to your customers one-on-one to gain deeper insight. In order to research a customer\'s current and future needs, it is important to listen for what the customer says is a problem, hassle, or unmet need. \nIn this regard, ask your customers to complete the following sentence: "I hate it when your product or service………………….. \nAlternatively, ask them to complete this sentence: "I wish I had a product or service that could solve my need for---------------------.\nThe above process is called as:',
    options: [
      "Analyzing the current state of your business",
      "Analyzing current customer needs using the focus-group research method",
      "Analyzing current and future customer needs using direct-observation methods.",
      "Analyzing current and future customer needs using in-depth interviews.",
    ],
    answer:
      "Analyzing current and future customer needs using in-depth interviews.",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Gain insight into future needs and potential new products and services by learning from users who have already solved the problem in a unique way. Often these users have already developed prototypes or work¬ing models of their ideas that could be beneficial in future development work. \nThe above process is called as:",
    options: [
      "Anticipating future customer needs using the lead-user research method",
      "Researching existing solutions within your category",
      "Researching existing solutions outside your category",
      "Researching and benchmarking excellence",
    ],
    answer:
      "Anticipating future customer needs using the lead-user research method",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Find ideas that have already been introduced in one country and bring them to another country before anyone else thinks of doing so. A team of scientists and physicians might be doing research on a cure for a certain disease, while another team halfway around the world has already found the cure. A product that is enjoying great sales in South America might just be entering the Chinese market but have yet to be introduced to the Australian market. This approach is not "stealing" since the ideas are already in the marketplace and are no longer "company secrets."\nThe above process is called as:',
    options: [
      "Anticipating future customer needs using the lead-user research method.",
      "Researching existing solutions within your category",
      "Researching existing solutions outside your category",
      "Researching and benchmarking excellence",
    ],
    answer: "Researching existing solutions within your category",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Financial institutions can research customer needs for insurance, estate planning, and prepaid funeral services in order to identify new categories in which they might be able to offer new products and services. \n•\tFood manufacturers can research the vitamin and herbal product categories to anticipate future needs and develop products that overlap these cate¬gories. \nThe above process is called as:",
    options: [
      "Anticipating future customer needs using the lead-user research method.",
      "Researching existing solutions within your category",
      "Researching existing solutions outside your category",
      "Researching and benchmarking excellence",
    ],
    answer: "Researching existing solutions outside your category",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "You should learn from the experts, both inside and outside of an indus¬try. For example, \n•\tlearn about e-commerce from FedEx\n•\tlearn about customer service from Four Seasons Hotels and Resorts \n•\tlearn about retail systems from Circuit City or Future Group \n•\tIdentify the experts in the particular challenge you are facing and find out how they addressed their similar challenges.\nThe above process is called as:",
    options: [
      "Anticipating future customer needs using the lead-user research method.",
      "Researching existing solutions within your category",
      "Researching existing solutions outside your category",
      "Researching and benchmarking excellence",
    ],
    answer: "Researching and benchmarking excellence",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What should be done to:\n1.\tanticipate how the landscape will change and how you can prepare for these changes\n2.\tanticipate what customers might want in the future\n3.\tface tremendous changes brought on by new technologies, more demanding customers, budget constraints, the aging population, and regulatory changes",
    options: [
      "R&D",
      "Trend watching",
      "Experimenting and exploring",
      "Software development",
    ],
    answer: "Trend watching",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "While holding Innovation Groups to turn your stimuli into insights, you have to combine insights in four key areas: \n1.\tcustomer needs, \n2.\temerging technology, \n3.\tthe marketplace, \nand what is the fourth one?",
    options: [
      "Your personal needs",
      "Your organization’s needs",
      "Employee needs",
      "Societal needs",
    ],
    answer: "Your organization’s needs",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'By discussing and agreeing upon the answers to the simple questions such as \n•\t"What do we want to do in the future?" \n•\t"Who do we want to become?" and \n•\t"What do we want to be famous for?" \na team is choosing its:',
    options: ["Goals", "Objectives", "Targets", "Vision"],
    answer: "Vision",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "While a few are looking up and planning for the future health of the orga¬nization, many are looking down, cutting costs and managing the day-to-day business. When does this short-term focus intensify?",
    options: [
      "When people are demotivated and frustrated",
      "When competitors dominate the market",
      "When customers go away",
      'When people face what they perceive to be "tough times"',
    ],
    answer: 'When people face what they perceive to be "tough times"',
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "For which countries and organizations, it is essential, to look to the future and identify strategic new ideas?",
    options: [
      "New organizations and developing countries",
      "Countries and organizations that are not blessed with rich resources or low cost structures",
      "Organizations in countries like Africa and Iraq",
      "Loss making companies",
    ],
    answer:
      "Countries and organizations that are not blessed with rich resources or low cost structures",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following signs we should not ignore which indicate what the future might hold?\n1.\tThere are clear signs that the aging population will require more health care\n2.\tThe fresh water resources are running low\n3.\tPeople are watching TV in the evening\n4.\tThe mobile phone Internet (m-commerce) era is upon us, \n5.\tThe global economy will flourish, \n6.\tThere will be computer chips in everything, \n7.\tOrganizations will employ more and more technology in the pursuit of efficiency and strength in the mar¬ketplace, \n8.\tThere will be more diverse work styles in the future.",
    options: [
      "We should not ignore any of them",
      "We should not ignore any of them except 3",
      "We can ignore 1 only",
      "We can ignore 5 only",
    ],
    answer: "We should not ignore any of them except 3",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Relying on only one source of information is like going fishing in a large pond and sitting in only one spot all day, hoping the fish will come to you. What is needed?",
    options: [
      "Fish in a small pond",
      "Not to go for fishing",
      "A bigger hook and movement around the pond",
      "Not to rely on any information",
    ],
    answer: "A bigger hook and movement around the pond",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Looking at trended sales information: \n•\tby geographic region to see which regions are strong or weak, \n•\tby distribution channel to see which channel is most or least beneficial to the business, \n•\tby month of the year to see when the business is strong or weak, \n•\tby customer group to see which groups are most and least important, and \n•\tby product line to see which line is strong or weak.\nThe above process is called as:",
    options: [
      "Analyzing the current state of your business",
      "Analyzing current customer needs using the focus-group research method",
      "Analyzing current and future customer needs using direct-observation methods.",
      "Analyzing current and future customer needs using in-depth interviews.",
    ],
    answer: "Analyzing the current state of your business",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Six to ten people are asked to participate in a round-table discussion in a specially designed room, which is outfitted with a two-way mirror. \n•\tThe client or those interested in hearing the customer feedback sit behind the two-way mirror in a sepa¬rate room while the participants and moderators are in the main room. \n•\tThe focus-group session usually lasts for two hours, during which the moderator leads the participants through a series of preplanned questions that are designed to tap into their attitudes regarding the chosen subject, product, or service.\nThe above process is called as:",
    options: [
      "Analyzing the current state of your business",
      "Analyzing current customer needs using the focus-group research method",
      "Analyzing current and future customer needs using direct-observation methods.",
      "Analyzing current and future customer needs using in-depth interviews.",
    ],
    answer:
      "Analyzing current customer needs using the focus-group research method",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "By going to the source, researchers can gain a deeper under-standing of customers' true attitudes and behaviors. For example, by watching how customers complete their banking forms, how consumers wash their cars, or how people prepare home-cooked meals, researchers are able to truly see what works, what doesn't work, and what might work in the future.\nThe above process is called as:",
    options: [
      "Analyzing the current state of your business",
      "Analyzing current customer needs using the focus-group research method",
      "Analyzing current and future customer needs using direct-observation methods.",
      "Analyzing current and future customer needs using in-depth interviews.",
    ],
    answer:
      "Analyzing current and future customer needs using direct-observation methods.",
    chapter: 7,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Consider the following questions:\n•\tHow can we use the power of branding to simplify our selling message?\n•\tHow can we use the power of branding to increase the consistency of our selling message?\n•\tHow can we use the power of branding to position our new pro¬grams to the employees in our organization?\nThis strategy is:",
    options: [
      "Extraordinary strategy # 7 Profit from the Power of Branding",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 8 Add Credibility",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 9 Create Magnetworks",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 6 Systemize with Modules",
    ],
    answer: "Extraordinary strategy # 7 Profit from the Power of Branding",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Consider the fol¬lowing questions:\n•\tHow can we eliminate unnecessary activities or "the crazy things we do" so that resources can be funneled toward more innovative activities?\n•\tHow can we simplify decision-making so those innovative ideas can make it through the system quickly?\n•\tHow can we take advantage of technology to quickly deliver something "distinctly new and better" to the customer?\nThis strategy is:',
    options: [
      "Extraordinary strategy # 7 Profit from the Power of Branding",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 8 Add Credibility",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 9 Create Magnet works",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 5 Pick Up the Pace",
    ],
    answer: "Extraordinary strategy # 5 Pick Up the Pace",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'In today\'s world, with more demanding customers, citizens, and employ¬ees, the ordinary is no longer good enough. Once consumers have tasted a better coffee, used a fancier toothbrush, or been served in less than a minute, it is difficult for them to accept what they perceive to be lower-quality products and services. Instead, they are looking for ---------------------, which means "the exceptional, surprising, and unusually great".',
    options: [
      "World class quality",
      "Reliability",
      "Longer life",
      "The extraordinary",
    ],
    answer: "The extraordinary",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In order to help to shift from the ordinary into the extraordinary, the  Gap Kids stores did in developing casual, trendy clothing for children. This Strategy is:",
    options: [
      "Target the Most Profitable Customer",
      "Offer Something Distinctly New and Better",
      "Set Your Innovation Priorities",
      "Make Sure It's Easy",
    ],
    answer: "Target the Most Profitable Customer",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Innovation is about introducing something "distinctly new and better" to the marketplace and succeeding in getting the customer to switch from what they are currently using to the new idea. \nThis strategy is:',
    options: [
      "Extraordinary strategy # 1 Target the Most Profitable Customer",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 2 Offer Something Distinctly New and Better",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 3 Set Your Innovation Priorities",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 4 Make Sure It's Easy",
    ],
    answer:
      "Extraordinary strategy # 2 Offer Something Distinctly New and Better",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Extraordinary strategy # 3 suggests that depending on how much risk your organization wants to undertake, you should have a mix of",
    options: ["Choices", "Options", "Varieties", "Priorities"],
    answer: "Priorities",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "People ideally want life to be easy. Many people have profited from pro¬viding easy services that others do not like to do, such as a simple service like barbeque cleaning, super scoopers for cleaning up after dogs, an errand service, or a tele-tutor service for school-age children who need assistance with their homework.\nThis strategy is:",
    options: [
      "Extraordinary strategy # 1 Target the Most Profitable Customer",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 2 Offer Something Distinctly New and Better",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 3 Set Your Innovation Priorities",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 4 Make Sure It's Easy",
    ],
    answer: "Extraordinary strategy # 4 Make Sure It's Easy",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Extraordinary Strategy 5 suggests that speed is ------------------------.",
    options: [
      "To remove the bottlenecks in your processes",
      "Simplifying decision-making",
      "Operating on customer hours",
      "Competitive advantage",
    ],
    answer: "Competitive advantage",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Say true or false:\n1.\tExtraordinary Strategy 6 suggests that by moving to                                      standardized parts, an organization can eliminate the wasted time and effort spent "reinventing the wheel" each time that part is needed.\n2.\tCustomers do not have a sense of power in the buying process if we move to standardized parts\n3.\tInternal processes are easily coordinated if we move to standardized parts.',
    options: [
      "1 is false, rest are true",
      "All are true",
      "2 is false, rest are true",
      "3 is false, rest are true",
    ],
    answer: "2 is false, rest are true",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Say true or false:\n1.\tA brand goes beyond the simple features of the product to create a distinct image.\n2.\tA cup of black coffee is only a cup of coffee, but by placing the particular brand name on it, we have the perception that the cup of black coffee is of higher quality. \n3.\tSport shoes with particular brand name and women's handbags with particular brand name command higher prices than similar products with less respected brand names. \n4.\tBranding does not deliver a guarantee of consistency",
    options: [
      "1 is false, rest are true",
      "2 is false, rest are true",
      "3 is false, rest are true",
      "4 is false, rest are true",
    ],
    answer: "4 is false, rest are true",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "1.\tInvestigate the potential of patenting the idea and, if the patent is granted, tell everyone.\n2.\tWin a prestigious award. Films that win at the Cannes Film Fes¬tival have instant credibility.\n3.\tHave a leading authority support your idea. Restaurants rely on restaurant critics to write wonderful reviews, writers covet Oprah Winfrey's endorsement, and toothpaste manufacturers pursue the endorsement of the Dental Association.\n4.\tProfile testimonials from satisfied customers",
    options: [
      "Extraordinary strategy # 5 Pick Up the Pace",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 6 Systemize with Modules",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 7 Profit from the Power of Branding",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 8 Add Credibility",
    ],
    answer: "Extraordinary strategy # 8 Add Credibility",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Consider  the following points:\n•\tNetwork within your organization\n•\tNetwork to learn from others\n•\tNetwork to share the infrastructure burden with other competi¬tors\n•\tNetwork to share research and development insights and respon¬sibilities. \n•\tNetwork to outsource\n•\tNetwork to enhance buying or selling power. \n•\tNetwork to create an organization of managed companies\n•\tNetwork to provide a hub or meeting place for others\nThis strategy is:",
    options: [
      "Extraordinary strategy # 7 Profit from the Power of Branding",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 8 Add Credibility",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 9 Create Magnetworks",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 6 Systemize with Modules",
    ],
    answer: "Extraordinary strategy # 9 Create Magnetworks",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Networks of competing and collaborating individuals or teams who inno¬vate together for mutual benefit are called as:",
    options: [
      "Quality circles",
      "Innovation groups",
      "Black belts",
      "Magnet works",
    ],
    answer: "Magnet works",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Consider the follow¬ing questions:\n•\tHow can we add prestige by winning an award?\n•\tHow can we gain support from leading authorities in our field?\n•\tHow could we enable potential customers to test this product or service?\nThis strategy is:",
    options: [
      "Extraordinary strategy # 7 Profit from the Power of Branding",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 8 Add Credibility",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 9 Create Magnet works",
      "Extraordinary strategy # 6 Systemize with Modules",
    ],
    answer: "Extraordinary strategy # 8 Add Credibility",
    chapter: 8,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the common between Oprah Winfrey (talk-show host and philanthropist), Tiger Woods (world-class golfer), and Nelson Mandela (South African activist and former president)?",
    options: [
      "They are innovators",
      "They are creative",
      "They like cricket",
      "They are passionate about their work",
    ],
    answer: "They are passionate about their work",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What will you observe when you have a chance to visit Seattle's Pike Street Fish Market and witness first-hand the workers?",
    options: ["Hard work", "Poverty", "High efficiency", "Passion"],
    answer: "Passion",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "We all know about or are familiar with people who have lost their pas¬sion--those individuals who appear to be detached from the world throughout their lives. \nWhy have they lost their passion? (Find out the wrong statement)",
    options: [
      "Too much choice",
      "Too many projects and not enough support",
      "Weak decision-making processes",
      "Fear and anxiety",
      "Too much free time",
    ],
    answer: "Too much free time",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'In an inter¬view to fill a vacant marketing position, one of the candidates for the position was a woman who was working in another department in the same company. When asked why she was interested in working with the marketing team, she replied, "The job pays better than my current job does." \nThere was no mention of any passion for the actual job or for learning more about how to market a product to a target consumer group. There was no mention of any interest in want¬ing to work with a team of energetic, passionate marketers! \nSo many people are focusing so much on extrinsic rewards instead of pursu¬ing a deeper attachment to the actual work.\nThis happens because:',
    options: [
      "No passion for the actual job",
      "No willingness for learning more about how to market a product to a target consumer group",
      "Tendency to focus so much on extrinsic rewards instead of pursu¬ing a deeper attachment to the actual work",
      "All the above",
    ],
    answer: "All the above",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      '•\t"Bob, give me an idea of how we could increase our inventory levels" \n•\t"We could look into scheduling three shifts instead of two."\n•\t"We thought of that already. Don\'t you have any practical ideas?"\nThese are the examples of:',
    options: [
      "Problem solving methods",
      "Continuous improvement",
      "Brainstorming",
      "Passion killers",
    ],
    answer: "Passion killers",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      '•\t"We haven\'t done that before" and \n•\t"We\'ve done that before!" \nThese are the examples of:',
    options: [
      "Problem solving methods",
      "Continuous improvement",
      "Brainstorming",
      "Passion killers",
    ],
    answer: "Passion killers",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Terrific\t\t\t\tYou're the best\nYou outdid yourself again\t\t\t\tGo for it\nKeep up the great work\t\t\t\tRight on\nWonderful\t\tThat's top rate\nThese are the examples of:",
    options: [
      "Passion supporters",
      "Employee motivation",
      "Morale boosters",
      "All the above",
    ],
    answer: "All the above",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The employees at Walt Disney World, or cast members, as they are often called, share their passion to create a wonderful experience for their:",
    options: ["Employees", "Customers or guests", "Suppliers", "Public"],
    answer: "Customers or guests",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'The employees are encouraged to be creative and make improvements on their own initiative. Co-founder knew that, in order to truly create an environment for innovation, he had to be willing to grant his employees the freedom to make decisions "on the spot," decisions that they felt were in the best interest of the orga¬nization.\nWhich organization are we talking about?',
    options: [
      "Walt Disney World",
      "Robert Bosch",
      "Southwest Airlines",
      "GSD&M",
    ],
    answer: "Southwest Airlines",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which organization believes that there is a relationship between physical environment, an energetic culture, and creative output?",
    options: [
      "Walt Disney World",
      "Robert Bosch",
      "Southwest Airlines",
      "GSD&M",
    ],
    answer: "GSD&M",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the purpose of some organizations, which are investigating or have built separate "creativ¬ity centers" within their existing office spaces? (These centers typically represent a cross between a resource center with access to magazines, videos, and other materials, and a community center, with comfortable chairs, strobe lights, toys, squirt guns, and even karaoke machines!)',
    options: [
      "To impress customers",
      "To create passionate environment",
      "to reduce attrition of employees",
      "To impress public and government agencies",
    ],
    answer: "To create passionate environment",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The reception area screams depression. Three tattered old office chairs surround one old coffee table. The remains of this morning's news¬paper (the business section is missing) lie beside two copies of Newsweek dated a few months ago. A lonely plant leaning slightly to the right stands limply beside the reception counter. On the reception counter is a small sign: Please ring bell.\nWhat will be the effect of the environment on employees/customers/suppliers?",
    options: [
      "They will get demotivated",
      "They will lose passion",
      "They will go away from the company",
      "All the above",
    ],
    answer: "All the above",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: '"Whatever it is, I\'m against it." Who said it?',
    options: ["Groucho Marx", "Karl Marx", "Einstein", "Mark Twain"],
    answer: "Groucho Marx",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "The employees at Walt Disney World are often called as:",
    options: ["Cast members", "Team Disney", "Beatles", "Disney associates"],
    answer: "Cast members",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "There are at least four key Passion Drivers at work (Find the wrong one)",
    options: [
      "Doing challenging work",
      "Having a sense of ownership in the ability to identify and imple¬ment",
      "Being recognized and rewarded for one's innovative work",
      "Having the opportunity not to work with other passionate people in a passionate environment",
    ],
    answer:
      "Having the opportunity not to work with other passionate people in a passionate environment",
    chapter: 9,
    marks: 1,
  },

  {
    question:
      "Why are the inventors of battery-operated cars and elec¬tric cars still waiting for the automobile and oil industry to accept alternative methods of transportation?",
    options: [
      "Customers feel that the car has poor pick up",
      "Customers are not thrilled at the shape of the car",
      "The car is expensive and charging takes long time",
      "The industry is not ready for the new idea",
    ],
    answer: "The industry is not ready for the new idea",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Who said it?\n"Never go to a meeting without a prototype."',
    options: ["Ratan Tata", "Narayana Murthy", "Dennis Boyle", "Stephen Covey"],
    answer: "Dennis Boyle",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Look at the following process:\n•\tDescribe the situation. \n•\tHighlight the problem. \n•\tExplain the implications if the problem intensifies or if the problem is not addressed immediately. \n•\tSet the stage for the introduc¬tion of your simple big Idea.\nThe above mentioned process is:",
    options: [
      "1st step in the six step selling process",
      "2nd step in the six step selling process",
      "3rd step in the six step selling process",
      "4th step in the six step selling process",
    ],
    answer: "1st step in the six step selling process",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      '•\t"We don\'t have any time." \n•\t"We don\'t have any money." \n•\t"It\'s too risky." \n•\t"It will ruin our image." \n•\t"We won\'t get the board\'s approval." \nThe above are:',
    options: [
      "Passion killers",
      "Brainstorming ideas",
      "Team members’ effort for status quo",
      "Difference of opinions",
    ],
    answer: "Passion killers",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Look at the example of Procter &amp; Gamble's Dryel product. \nZip it.\nAdd 1-4 garments to the Dryel Fabric Protection Bag. Bag should not be more than half-full to allow garments to tumble freely. Unfold Dryel cleaning cloth and add to bag. Zip the bag and then place in the dryer.\nSteam it.\nTumble in dryer on medium heat for 30 minutes to activate the steam-cleaning environment, removing odors and protecting against shrinking, stretching &amp; fading.\nWear it.\nClothes should be slightly damp when removing them from the bag. Promptly hang or wear clean and fresh garments to help wrinkles fall out. Throw away cleaning cloths after use, but save the Dryel Bag for next time. It is designed to last up to 25 loads.\nThe concept behind this product is to encourage consumers to forgo the existing method and simply use their clothes dryers instead. All they have to do is place their clothes in a Dryel bag with a Dryel sheet and then place this bag in the dryer. \nWhy was the product not accepted by the customer?",
    options: [
      "Expensive method",
      "Not advertised properly",
      "Too complicated process",
      "Procter & Gamble was not sure how to convince consumers to switch to this product",
    ],
    answer:
      "Procter & Gamble was not sure how to convince consumers to switch to this product",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Look at the example of the television advertisements for long-distance telephone services. Many of the ads focused on the price of the service, comparing one company's plans to others' plans. What was missing in these ads?",
    options: [
      "Switching plan to make it easy for the customer",
      "Customer did not get the meaning of the ad",
      "Bad reputation of the brand",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Switching plan to make it easy for the customer",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      '"Five frogs are sitting on a log. Four decide to jump off. How many are left?" You might think this is a simple riddle. "Why, one frog, of course," you respond, "That was an easy and straightforward question.” It is not until someone else in the crowd answers "five frogs" that you stop and examine the riddle again. You see, even though four frogs decided to jump off, there is nothing in the riddle to indicate that they actually jumped.\nWhat is the moral of the story?',
    options: [
      "Frogs are undecided",
      "Frogs are afraid to jump",
      "There is difference of opinion between frogs",
      "There is a big difference between deciding to do something and actually doing it",
    ],
    answer:
      "There is a big difference between deciding to do something and actually doing it",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Great ideas are not "innovative" unless they are:',
    options: [
      "Properly presented",
      "Properly sold",
      "Success¬fully implemented",
      "Accepted by skeptics",
    ],
    answer: "Success¬fully implemented",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "McDonald's restaurants generally recog¬nized as leading the way into fast-food heaven. Now, McDonald's needs to deal with the very serious threat of mad cow dis¬ease and the dire impact that perceptions about this disease could have on its hamburger business. \nWhat is the moral of the story?",
    options: [
      "One needs to be constantly innovating",
      "Solution must be found for mad cow disease",
      "Need to prove that mad cow disease is not due to hamburger",
      "Sustainable competitive advantage is because of hamburger",
    ],
    answer: "One needs to be constantly innovating",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Bausch &amp; Lomb, well known for leading the way with contact lens solutions, needs to deal with the trend toward disposable lenses and laser eye surgery.\nWhat is the action necessary?",
    options: [
      "Prove that laser eye surgery is harmful",
      "Prove that disposable lenses damage the eyesight",
      "Sustainable competitive advantage is because of disposable lenses and laser eye surgery.",
      "One needs to be constantly innovating",
    ],
    answer: "One needs to be constantly innovating",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The first criterion among the six BIG Picture Criteria is that the idea must be:",
    options: ["Distinctly new and better", "Proven", "Profitable", "Simple"],
    answer: "Simple",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Say true or false:\n1.\tProjects that represent products or services to be introduced to the marketplace in the next two years might be subject to different cri¬teria than projects or services that will be introduced later.\n2.\tThe idea must be quickly and easily implemented\n3.\tSo many great organizations and the people aligned with them fail to reach their full potential due to lack of action\n4.\tWe should not celebrate and enjoy our successes because we should be aware that the world is constantly evolving and that we therefore need to be constantly innovating.",
    options: [
      "1 is false, rest are true",
      "2 is false, rest are true",
      "3 is false, rest are true",
      "4 is false, rest are true",
    ],
    answer: "4 is false, rest are true",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Say true or false:\n1.\tNot everyone is the same, and not everyone will focus on the same aspects of your idea.\n2.\tIt is rare that an idea is not accepted at its initial presentation.\n3.\tMany ideas are rejected because they are misunderstood\n4.\tOne can use a prototype to make the  idea come alive for the  audience.",
    options: [
      "1 is false, rest are true",
      "2 is false, rest are true",
      "3 is false, rest are true",
      "4 is false, rest are true",
    ],
    answer: "2 is false, rest are true",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why did it take Kellogg's over a decade to con¬vince consumers to switch from eating hot cereal to eating cold cereal?",
    options: [
      "Customers did not like the taste",
      "Cold cereal is not conventional",
      "Cold cereal is injurious to health",
      "Consumers were mentally not ready for the new idea",
    ],
    answer: "Consumers were mentally not ready for the new idea",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Create the demand for your idea as a solution to the problem or situa¬tion. When presenting, spend at least ---- percent of your time selling the problem and all its implications.",
    options: ["20", "25", "30", "50"],
    answer: "25",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },

  {
    question:
      "What is the best way to deal with skeptics who create many obstacles for you because you are a different thinker?",
    options: [
      "to question the overall strategy and to advocate a completely new philosophy",
      "to confront them",
      "to ignore them",
      "to question their locus standi",
    ],
    answer:
      "to question the overall strategy and to advocate a completely new philosophy",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What was Ted Turner's new idea, which was ridiculed in U.S. as Chicken Noodle Network?",
    options: [
      "Chicken Biryani with paneer",
      "Fried Chicken in different taste",
      "Company Website on the Internet",
      "24 hour news channel",
    ],
    answer: "24 hour news channel",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why is Starbucks so successful that it has more loyal customers than any other retailer in the country and on an average, a Starbucks customer visits a Starbucks 18 times per month?",
    options: [
      "They offer coffee better than Nestle’",
      "Their coffee is cheaper",
      "Their coffee is liked by upper middle class",
      "Innovative idea of creating coffee shops everywhere",
    ],
    answer: "Innovative idea of creating coffee shops everywhere",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 1 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “Look for good and innovative ideas among your competitors and within your own industry”.\nWhat is the different thinking?\nIn rule 1 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “Look for good and innovative ideas among your competitors and within your own industry”.\nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "Deliberately look for ideas and inspiration for new products and services in totally different industries.",
      "Never look for ideas and inspiration for new products and services among competitors",
      "Deliberately look for ideas and inspiration for new products and services in your attics and old files only",
      "Never look for ideas and inspiration for new products and services within your own industry",
    ],
    answer:
      "Deliberately look for ideas and inspiration for new products and services in totally different industries.",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 2 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “the target group for your products or services should be as wide as possible. Your range needs to be not too expensive, not too cheap and of interest to as many people as possible”\nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "The target group for your products or services should be as small as possible",
      "Your range needs to be cheap and of interest to only specific people",
      "Always be in the live center of the market",
      "Get out of the dead center of the market.",
    ],
    answer: "Get out of the dead center of the market.",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 3 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “try to carry out as many profit-making activities as possible under your own steam”.\nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "Do not carry out any profit-making activities under your own steam",
      "Let your customers carry out profit making activities",
      "Focus on the activities where you are really world-class and leave the rest to suppliers, partners or your own customers",
      "Let your suppliers carry out profit making activities",
    ],
    answer:
      "Focus on the activities where you are really world-class and leave the rest to suppliers, partners or your own customers",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 4 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “Focus on your existing customers and strive for continual optimization of the products and services you already offer them. This has always worked in the past, so it cannot be wrong”\nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "Escape the typical head-on competition by creating completely new markets",
      "Do not Focus on your existing customers, look for new customers",
      "Win the head-on competition by reducing prices",
      "Go out of the way to sell your products to new customers",
    ],
    answer:
      "Escape the typical head-on competition by creating completely new markets",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 5 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “You respect the geographical borders of your industry. For example, if your industry centers exclusively on a regional alignment, you tailor your products and services to the requirements of local customers”.\nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "Never swim against the geographical alignment of your industry",
      "Deliberately set out to swim against the geographical alignment of your industry and create your own economic boost",
      "Never tailor your products and services to the requirements of local customers",
      "Always tailor your products and services to the requirements of outsider customers",
    ],
    answer:
      "Deliberately set out to swim against the geographical alignment of your industry and create your own economic boost",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 6 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “Expand your existing range by simply adding products and services that are already familiar and standard for your industry”.\nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "Never expand your existing range by adding products and services that are new for your industry",
      "Never expand your existing range by adding non-standard products",
      "Combine products and services from two different industries to offer a completely new mix.",
      "Mix and match your existing products to make a cheaper product",
    ],
    answer:
      "Combine products and services from two different industries to offer a completely new mix.",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 7 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “Following the principle of spreading risks, you create a wide portfolio of products and services hoping to counter¬balance a weak performance in one area through good performance in others”.\nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "Mix and match your existing products to make a cheaper product",
      "Be bold, find a niche or carve one out for yourself. Create your own temporary monopoly.",
      "It is very risky to follow the principle of spreading risks",
      "It is very risky to create own temporary monopoly, so do not create a wide portfolio of products and services",
    ],
    answer:
      "Be bold, find a niche or carve one out for yourself. Create your own temporary monopoly.",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 8 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “You accept existing product concepts and strive to optimize your range of products and services within these limits”. \nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "Do not optimize your range of products and services",
      "Do not create a wide portfolio of products and services",
      "You question established product concepts and gain new scope for innovative and cool products and services.",
      "Never question established product concepts and never gain new scope new products and services",
    ],
    answer:
      "You question established product concepts and gain new scope for innovative and cool products and services.",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 9 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “You focus on your products and their function -- design is the least important step and serves solely to make products more aesthetically pleasing”.\nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "Do not focus on your products and their function",
      "It is very risky to follow the principle of spreading risks",
      "Mix and match your existing products to make a cheaper product",
      "You take advantage of unusual design to differentiate your products and make them successful",
    ],
    answer:
      "You take advantage of unusual design to differentiate your products and make them successful",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 10 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “You rely on rational argument and the persuasive power of your products (functionality, performance, quality etc.) to win customers”.\nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "Add some¬thing more to the rational arguments, an element hardly ever talked about in the business environment: emotions and experiences.",
      "Always tailor your products and services to the requirements of outsider customers",
      "Win the head-on competition by reducing prices",
      "Never rely on rational argument and the persuasive power of your products",
    ],
    answer:
      "Add some¬thing more to the rational arguments, an element hardly ever talked about in the business environment: emotions and experiences.",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 11 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “You keep on expanding the range of products and services you offer and introducing even more price models. Your aim is to ensure that the customers have an ever-increasing range and variety of products and services to choose from”.\nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "You cut out the frills",
      "Offer clarity and simplicity that your customers will not be able to resist",
      "Simplify, focus on the essentials",
      "All the above",
    ],
    answer: "All the above",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In rule 12 of different thinking, conventional thinking is “You take the established price model for your industry as a given and strive for optimization within these limits”. \nWhat is the different thinking?",
    options: [
      "Instead of wasting your energy trying to optimize the established price model for your industry, offer little bit cheaper",
      "Instead of wasting your energy trying to optimize the established price model for your industry, offer little bit more expensive",
      "Instead of wasting your energy trying to optimize the established price model for your industry or to be just that little bit cheaper than your competitors do, you create your own price model.",
      "Look for the price models in developed countries",
    ],
    answer:
      "Instead of wasting your energy trying to optimize the established price model for your industry or to be just that little bit cheaper than your competitors do, you create your own price model.",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },

  {
    question:
      "Say true or false:\n1.\tInnovation cannot be external to the organization\n2.\tThe organization as a whole must be ready to absorb innovation.\n3.\tInnovative companies should be built into shared innovation mindset\n4.\tTeams should be  working together on new solutions that were tested before",
    options: [
      "1 is false, rest are true",
      "2 is false, rest are true",
      "3 is false, rest are true",
      "4 is false, rest are true",
    ],
    answer: "4 is false, rest are true",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Say true or false:\n1.\tManagers must involve the entire staff (down to the admin assistant), where you see a collective interest and care for the innovation project. \n2.\tLesson learning on successful innovation projects must be shared across departments and regions, side by side with insights on the projects that failed. \n3.\tInnovative ideas are surely essential but most of them tend to fail.\n4.\tThere is no need to strike a balance between continuity and innovation.",
    options: [
      "1 is false, rest are true",
      "2 is false, rest are true",
      "3 is false, rest are true",
      "4 is false, rest are true",
    ],
    answer: "4 is false, rest are true",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "From the following list, which type of executives are good ones?",
    options: [
      "Those who can get short-term results and do not have a clue where they are going to take the company in the future",
      "Those who have a great ten-year plan but are going to be out of business in ten months",
      "Those who can get short-term results in conjunction with a vision for the future",
      "Those who can get long term results and are less worried about the short term",
    ],
    answer:
      "Those who can get short-term results in conjunction with a vision for the future",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Today’s leaders must be willing to invest in something that will someday:",
    options: [
      "Improve all that they worked so hard to achieve",
      "Replace all that they worked so hard to achieve",
      "Make their position flexible",
      "Result in their progress",
    ],
    answer: "Replace all that they worked so hard to achieve",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Nothing stops an organization faster than people who believe that:",
    options: [
      "Innovation is the life and death matter for the organization",
      "Everyone is creative",
      "The way they worked yesterday is the best way to work tomorrow",
      "Creativity is contagious, pass it on",
    ],
    answer: "The way they worked yesterday is the best way to work tomorrow",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "It lets business leaders assess potential business changes before they happen. Using past business data, users can see how different changes would affect various aspects of their business.\nWhat are we talking about?",
    options: ["Innovation", "Creativity", "Invention", "What if analysis"],
    answer: "What if analysis",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'It is where you allow your subconscious mind to process all the facts and send you signals in the form of your "sixth sense”. This allows non-rational factors to be brought into the mix, which is sometimes the only way forward.\nWhat are we talking about?',
    options: [
      "Transcendental meditation",
      "Creativity",
      "Morning prayer",
      "Intuition",
    ],
    answer: "Intuition",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the organization aspires to maintaining world-class status over the longer term, all four of following roles must be present in balanced amounts.\n•\tProducers: \n•\tImplementers: \n•\tInnovators: \n•\t--------------------",
    options: ["Leaders", "Managers", "Integrators", "Suppliers"],
    answer: "Integrators",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Left brain thinkers will:",
    options: [
      "Feel or sense something is right and act immediately",
      "Analyze anything half to death before acting",
      "Stop and analyze the pros and cons after taking action",
      "Do it first and then talk",
    ],
    answer: "Analyze anything half to death before acting",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Right brain thinkers will:",
    options: [
      "Feel or sense something is right and act immediately",
      "Analyze anything half to death before acting",
      "Think twice before doing anything",
      "Not do anything before logical thinking",
    ],
    answer: "Feel or sense something is right and act immediately",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The future of any organization rests solely on its ability to improve quality, profits and levels of customer service in the short run. However, in the long run, it must have ability to:",
    options: [
      "Invest in more machines and people",
      "Develop the breakthrough innovations that are going to form the foundation for the organization",
      "Give more dividends to the shareholders",
      "Increase the wages and incentives to workers",
    ],
    answer:
      "Develop the breakthrough innovations that are going to form the foundation for the organization",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Fill in the blanks:\nIt requires willingness on the part of -------------------in order to stay competitive today and in the future, to accept the challenge to create an organization in which people can excel while simultaneously managing the present and creating their own futures.",
    options: ["Workers", "Leader", "CEO", "Black belts"],
    answer: "Leader",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Fill in the blanks:\nThe key to to stay competitive today and in the future has more to do with people and their relationships with ------------------- and less to do with products and technologies than most people will realize at first glance.",
    options: ["Superiors", "Workers", "Each other", "Family"],
    answer: "Each other",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "During a business transformation, what takes place that realigns people, processes and technology seamlessly to new strategic objectives? Tick the best option.",
    options: ["Workers’ strike", "RBI policy", "Change", "Recession"],
    answer: "Change",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why must both managers and researchers regard innovation as a ‘life-and-death’ matter for a firm?",
    options: [
      "It is necessary",
      "Threat of competition",
      "Recession",
      "Change",
    ],
    answer: "Threat of competition",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which government office is using multimodal biometrics--fingerprints, iris scans, and photographs--to build the world's most ambitious identity database?",
    options: ["ZipDial", "Innoz", "Goonj", "UIDAI"],
    answer: "UIDAI",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "It gives brands a toll-free number that they can publicize for consumers to dial into. On the consumer dialing the toll-free number, the call rings once and disconnects and then the consumer receives an SMS with more information on the marketing campaign. Which company are we talking about?",
    options: ["Mahindra and Mahindra", "Idea", "ZipDial", "AirTel"],
    answer: "ZipDial",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which company is known for their flagship product called, 55444, which is an offline search engine, one can send a query via SMS and get the answers on SMS?",
    options: ["Cloudnine", "Eram Scientific", "Innoz", "ZipDial"],
    answer: "Innoz",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which company channels excess resources from urban households to impoverished, rural, and disaster-struck areas, in exchange for clothes, furniture, household goods, and medical supplies, village and slum communities self-organize and build schools, roads, and toilet facilities?",
    options: ["Bosch", "Goonj", "Red Cross", "Cloudnine"],
    answer: "Goonj",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Eram Scientific is known for improving the country's ----------------network.",
    options: [
      "Communication",
      "Innovation projects",
      "Marriage bureau",
      "Public toilet",
    ],
    answer: "Public toilet",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which company’s CANScript technology re-creates an artificial environment for a patient's tumor sample and tests various drugs on it directly, allowing the company to arrive at a personalized treatment in less than a week?",
    options: ["Mitra Biotech", "Biocon Ltd.", "Novo Nordisk", "Biogen Idec"],
    answer: "Mitra Biotech",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which company’s disruptive platform helps screen and hire programmers through online coding tests and contests, thus matching best performers from around the globe to business titans?",
    options: [
      "Naukri.com",
      "Jobstreet.com",
      "Interviewstreet",
      "Tata Consultancy Services",
    ],
    answer: "Interviewstreet",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which company is known for delivering world-class services and health care to expectant mothers?",
    options: [
      "Apollo Hospitals",
      "Wockhardt Hospitals",
      "Cloud Atlas",
      "Cloudnine",
    ],
    answer: "Cloudnine",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who has created “Glass, which is making wearables the next computing trend”?",
    options: ["Cloudnine", "Samsung", "Nokia", "Google"],
    answer: "Google",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Sustainability VP Hannah Jones of which company says:\n"Flyknit could turn the industry on its head?"',
    options: ["Bata", "Air India", "Spice Jet", "Nike"],
    answer: "Nike",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which company introduced same-day shipping in seven major U.S. markets more than three years ago?",
    options: ["Flipkart", "SnapDeal", "Myntra", "Amazon"],
    answer: "Amazon",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Whose original idea was to enable credit card transactions on mobile devices?",
    options: ["Nokia", "Samsung", "LG", "Square"],
    answer: "Square",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Retina display belong to which organization?",
    options: ["Google", "LG", "Apple", "Wipro"],
    answer: "Apple",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who boasted that his new Kindle Fire HD's 254 pixels came with an \"Advanced True Wide polarizing filter?",
    options: ["Amazon CEO", "Microsoft CEO", "Google CEO", "Apple CEO"],
    answer: "Amazon CEO",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "FuelBand belongs to which company?",
    options: ["Google", "Apple", "Samsung", "Nike"],
    answer: "Nike",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
];
